

JIGAR ASHAR

2202, Cherish Building, Citi Of Joy, JSD Road, Mulund West, Mumbai, Maharashtra 400080

Phone: +91 - 9769507504 | +91 - 7021178068

Email: jigarpashar@gmail.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jigarashar/

Website: https://jigarashar.com/

DOB: 18/11/1992

Professional Summary

Versatile Business Head with exceptional business sense and in-depth understanding of IT infrastructure and operations, best practices and strategies. Offering 5 years of progressive experience in the field and seeking a new professional challenge with a growing company.

Skills

Budget development

Program management

Market research

Graphic design

Product marketing specialist

Strategic thinker

Multivariate testing knowledge

Sales training

Adobe Creative Cloud proficiency

Effective relationship building

Business development

Corporate presentations

Website optimization

Business planning

Digital marketing

Creative and innovative

Natural leader

Strategic marketing

Web 2.0 savvy

Case studies

Sales strategies

Department Policies & Procedure Implementation

Decision Making & Judgment

Project management

Web development

Web user interfaces

Work History

Business Head

May 2018 - Current

Mumbai, Maharashtra

Grow For Sure Technologies

- Set and monitored annual budgets for departments and the business as a whole.
- Analyzed business developments and monitored market trends.
- Contributed ideas to concept development, strategic planning and business operations.
- Wrote professional business correspondence and produced reports detailing updates.

- Streamlined costs through proactive examination and improvement of operations.
- Created and optimized policies and programs in line with corporate vision.
- Developed and implemented successful strategies for building company sales.
- Directed product development using in-depth knowledge of vendor landscape and industry insight.
- Directed hiring, training and performance evaluations for marketing and sales staff and supervised daily activities.
- Preserved brand integrity by monitoring the consistency and quality of marketing content.
- Prepared and gave presentations to clients and other project stakeholders.
- Analyzed usage patterns to understand ways in which customers used company products and services.
- Maintained an organized office space.
- Gathered user feedback and made recommendations.
- Proposed technical feasibility solutions for new functional designs and suggested options for performance improvement of technical objects.
- Directed onsite training for business users to maximize productivity.
- Provided methodologies for object-oriented software development and efficient database design.
- Trained designers on computer graphic design programs such as Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop.
- Planned project concepts by researching and studying information.
- Managed day-to-day business operations and made strategic decisions.
- Generated new ideas with limited direction and varied internal client needs.
- Developed marketing and sales strategies to maximize business success.
- Planned, organized and scheduled work.
- Researched new technologies, software packages and hardware products for use in website projects.
- Tested websites and performed troubleshooting prior to deployment.
- Implemented Google Campaigns and SEO for various types of websites.
- Hands-on experience using UNIX and Apache web servers.
- Optimized web assets for speed and performance.
- Strengthened the company brand and identity by creating a distinctive websites and logos for clients.

Assistant Vice President

Feb 2017 - Apr 2018

Eitopper Edutech Pvt. Ltd.

Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Managing the complete IT infrastructure of the company, which included networking, monitoring and troubleshooting.
- Designing website for the company and managing all enquiries and complaints received on the website.
- Managing SEO and SMO of the company and clients.
- Managing Sales Team and Providing Technical Training of the websites developed by the company for its clients.
- Managing Online Marketing along with Digital Marketing, SMS/Email Marketing and PPC.

- Handling group of Developers and assigning (slotting) them tasks with regards to website development as required by the company and clients.
- Analysing the data using pivot and creating charts and sheets to project the future of the business, company and projects.
- Resolved issues and completed the required follow-up processes.
- Created a new secure online portal for workers and implemented other new technology to improve interdepartmental communications.
- Created and made appropriate documentation for annual budgets and senior leadership goals.
- Assisted and supported Board Members in all matters of administration, management, planning and policies.
- Allocated work assignments and tasks to comprehensively manage administrative projects.
- Attended board and committee meetings and took meeting minutes to create detailed records of various meetings and decisions.
- Established and maintained effective, lucrative relationships with customers.
- Created reports and presentations detailing business development activities.
- Negotiated, prepared and signed contracts with customers.
- Devised effective marketing, sales and other promotional initiatives.
- Recommended network security standards to management.
- Advocated for end-users to perform testing and problem analysis for server, desktop and IT infrastructure work.
- Evaluated and resolved Applications and Website problems in an efficient manner to minimize downtime.
- Identified potential risk and developed resolution processes.

Freelancer May 2015 - Jan 2017

Mumbai, Maharashtra

- Creating portfolio websites for customers and clients.
- Gathered user feedback and made recommendations.
- Handling group of Developers and assigning (slotting) them tasks with regards to website development as required by the company and clients.
- Accomplished customer requirements for computer graphic design programs on Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator and Adobe Photoshop.
- Provided IT consultation to various firms, SME's and Corporates with regards to Software, Networking,
 Digital Marketing and other IT related queries
- Prepared and gave presentations to clients and other project stakeholders.
- Directed onsite training for business users to maximize productivity.
- Resolved issues and completed the required follow-up processes.
- Generated new ideas with limited direction and varied clientele needs.

Education

Bachelor Of Science In Information Technology - Web Development

2015

Mulund College Of Commerce – Affiliated to Mumbai University

Mumbai, Maharashtra

12th: Commerce 2012

NES College Of Arts, Science And Commerce – Maharashtra Board

Mumbai, Maharashtra

10th - Maharashtra Board

2010

Fatima High School - Maharashtra

Mumbai, Maharashtra

Accomplishments

- DSC Experts Web Based CRM Software
 - Link: console.dscexperts.com
 - CRM Software to manage customers of the client, thereby enabling smooth and automated process for the web application.
 - o Role: Manage Flowchart, UI and UX development, Assist team on flow of data
- Video Verify Me Video Verification Android App
 - Video Verify Me App lets you record the verification statements of your customers for the product, services and schemes that you sell.
 - App Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.growforsure.videoverifyme
 - Web Link: https://videoverifyme.com
 - o Developed with team of 3 Developers in span of 3 Months
 - Role: Supervise and Mange team, Visualize and build the UI and UX for the App, Guide the Team and explain them workflow, Create Pricing Plan to sustain growth and understand the cost/budgeting and other resources used for the app
- Zumbad Dating App for LGBTQI Community
 - App Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.growforsure.zumbad
 - Web Link: https://zumbad.com
 - Zumbad is a Social Search and Dating Mobile App that enables users to like or dislike different users, and permits users to speak if each parties swiped to the right. The app is designed to be used as a hookup and dating app for Straight and LGBTQI Community.
 - Planning and Creation of the App
 - Market research for Competitors in the similar industry segment
- Meddco.com Search portal for treatment of various kind of diseases
 - o Developing entire portal on Core PHP as per clients requirement
 - Web Link: https://meddco.com
 - App Link: https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.meddco

- Resolved various product issue through alpha and beta testing for various admin interface and applications.
- Supervised team of 15 staff members.
- Collaborated with team of 6 in the development of Zoopcall App.

Hobbies

- Movies
- TV Series
- PC and PlayStation Games
- Football
- Music
- Internet